Physic Materials are materials that instead
物理マテリアル (Physics Material) は
of effecting the appearance of a game object
ゲームオブジェクトの見映えに影響する代わりに
they effect the way that the object reacts
オブジェクトが物理エンジンに対してオブジェクトがどう反応するかに
to the physics engine. Consider the difference
影響するマテリアルです。
between how a basketball and a bowling ball
バスケットボールとボウリングボールで、跳ね方が
might bounce. Whilst there is a difference
どう違うか考えてみてください。重さにも違いが
in their mass, their surfaces are also
ありますが、表面もまた大きく違いがあり、
very different and they react to other
他の表面とも違う反応を示す場合が
surfaces very differently. Physic materials
あります。物理マテリアルは
can be created from the Create button
プロジェクトパネルの Create ボタンにより
on the project panel.
作成することが出来ます。
And they're edited in the inspector to
そしてインスペクタで編集することで
control how the surface reacts to another
他の表面に対してどのように反応するか
surface. They do this by controlling friction.
制御できます。これを行なうためには摩擦を制御します。
Dynamic Friction is how much friction
Dynamic Friction （動摩擦係数）はオブジェクトが動く時に
exists whilst the object is moving
どの程度の摩擦があるかを示し、
and Static Friction is how much
Static Friction （静摩擦係数）は
force is required in order to move the
オブジェクトを静的な位置から
object from a static position.
移動するのに必要な力を示します。
Bounciness does exactly what it sounds like.
Bounciness （跳ね返り係数）は名前と同じ働きをします。
It controls how bouncy the object is.
オブジェクトがいかに跳ねやすいか制御します。
And the Friction Combine settings control
そして Friction Combine 設定は
how they respond to another object
特定のマテリアルをもった別のオブジェクトにどのように反応するか
with a certain material. Friction Direction
制御します。Friction Directionにより、
will allow you to control friction
特定軸での摩擦を
in a particular axis and the dynamic
制御できて、Dynamic Friction 2 および
and static friction 2 properties
Static Friction 2 プロパティは
will give you control over those three axes.
この 3 つの軸に対する制御ができます。
In this example we've applied this
このサンプルでは、この
particular physic material to our power cube
特定の物理マテリアルを powerCube および
and our work bench.
bench_work にアタッチしています。
The physic material is applied to the
物理マテリアルは
collider in any given game object
任意のゲームオブジェクトのコライダに適用され
and you can see that there's a slot for
コライダの設定にマテリアルのスロットがあることを
material within the collider settings.
確認できます。
You can see that if I press play,
Play ボタンを押下した後、
it bounces slightly and is also very slippery.
わずかに跳ねて、そしてとても滑りやすくなっています。
This is because I've used 0 for dynamic
この理由は Dynamic Friction および Static Friction に 0 を
and static friction, meaning there's nothing
使用したためであり、この場合は
stopping it from slipping around and
滑ることを防ぐものがなく、
I've also made it slightly bouncy.
さらに跳ねやすくしています。
If I make it very bouncy
ここで大きく跳ねやすくすると
then it's going to bounce off of the table.
これで跳ねてテーブルから落ちます。
And for example if I wanted to restrict
そして例えば、もし動作を特定の軸だけ
it's movement in a particular axis
制限したい場合
so I can see that the X axis is the direction
X 軸が滑っている方向であることが
in which it's sliding, so what I could do
確認できるので、出来ることとしては
is go back to that material and I'll set
マテリアルに戻って
my friction direction of X to 1 and
X の Friction Direction を 1 にして
increase the dynamic friction. I'm going to turn
Dynamic Friction を増加させます。
bounciness back down to a lower number
Bounciness はより小さい数字にして
so that it doesn't bounce off the table.
テーブルから跳ねて落ちないようにします。
And you can see that it's slowing to a halt
これで徐々に静止するようになり、
because of the amount of friction involved there.
これは設定した Friction の大きさが影響しています。
So we could make that slightly lower
このため、より小さくしてみると
and you can see it begins to slide.
再び滑り始めることが確認できます。
So hopefully you can see that with
これによって
physic materials you can completely control
物理マテリアルにより
the surface of an object
オブジェクトの表面と他の表面とどう反応するか
and how it responds to others.
完全に制御できることが分かります。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)